<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading on Brilliun&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://brilliun.com/categories/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reading on Brilliun&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 22:36:35 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://brilliun.com/categories/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Microservices: Designing Fine-Grained Systems - Part I</title>
      <link>https://brilliun.com/2019/06/building-microservices-designing-fine-grained-systems-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 22:36:35 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brilliun.com/2019/06/building-microservices-designing-fine-grained-systems-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1. Microservices Many organizations have found that by embracing fine-grained, microservice architectures, they can deliver software faster and embrace newer technologies. Microservices give us significantly more freedom to react and make different decisions, allowing us to respond faster to the inevitable change that impacts all of us.
Chapter 3. How to Model Services To be able to work out the valuation of the company, though, the finance employees need information about the stock we hold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Data Intensive Applications Part1</title>
      <link>https://brilliun.com/2018/05/designing-data-intensive-applications-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 22:22:54 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brilliun.com/2018/05/designing-data-intensive-applications-part1/</guid>
      <description>CH01. Reliable, Scalable, and Maintainable Applications About Data System We can think of any kind of databases, queues, or caches as a data system. Nowadays, these tools are optimized for a variety of different uses, and they no longer neatly fit into their origin categories
For example, there are data stores that are also used as message queues (Redis), and there are message queues with database-like durability guarantees (Apache Kafka).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Performance Browser Networking</title>
      <link>https://brilliun.com/2016/12/high-performance-browser-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 22:38:02 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brilliun.com/2016/12/high-performance-browser-networking/</guid>
      <description>Ch01. Primer on Latency and Bandwidth  Latency
The time from the source sending a packet to the destination receiving it
Bandwidth
Maximum throughput of a logical or physical communication path
 Latency, not bandwidth, is the performance bottleneck for most web‐ sites!
To increase bandwidth, while it might not be cheap, we have multiple strategies available, like adding more fiber links.
Improving latency, on the other hand, is a very different story.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>